When designing a layer for
a conv layer, you
might have to pick.
Do you want a
one-by-three filter
or three-by-three
or five-by-five,
or do you want a polling layer?
What the exception network
does is it says, why
don't you do them all?
This makes the network
architecture more complicated,
but it also works
remarkably well.
Let's see how this works.
Let's say for the second
example that you have
input a 28 by 28 by
192-dimensional volume.
What the inception network
or what an inception
layer says is,
instead of choosing
what filter size
you want in a conv layer
or even do you want
a convolutional layer or
polling layer,
let's do them all.
What if you can use a
one-by-one convolution,
and that will output a
28 by 28 by something,
let's say, 28 by
28 by 64 output,
and you just have
a volume there?
But maybe you also want
to try a three by three,
and that might output
a 20 by 28 by 128.
Then what you do is just
stack up this second volume
next to the first volume.
To make the dimensions match up,
let's make this
same convolution,
so the output dimension
is still 28 by 28,
same as the input dimension
in terms of height and width,
but 28 by 28 but in
this example 128.
Maybe you might say, well,
I want to hedge my bets.
Maybe a five-by-five filter
works better so
let's do that too,
and have that output
a 28 by 28 by 32.
Again, you use the
same convolution
to keep the dimensions same.
Maybe you don't want
convolutional layer.
Let's apply pulling, and
that has some other output,
and let's stack that up as well.
Here, pulling outputs
28 by 28 by 32.
Now, in order to make all
the dimensions match,
you actually need to use
padding for Max pooling.
This is an unusual form of
polling because if you want
the input to have
height and worth 28
by 28 and have the output,
match the dimension and
everything else also by 28 by 28,
then you need to use
same padding as well as a
stride of one for polling.
This detail might seem
a bit funny to you now,
but let's keep going.
We'll make this all work later.
But with a inception
module like this,
you can input some volume
and output, in this
case, I guess,
if you add up all these numbers,
32 plus 32 plus 128 plus
64 that's equal to 256.
You will have one inception
module input 28 by 28 by 192,
and output 28 by 28 by 256.
This is the heart of
the inception network,
which is due to Cristian Zagoi,
We Lu Yantin Zia,
Pi, Scott Reed, Dragoma,
Anglov Dmitri Rhon Vincent
VanKok, and Andrew Rabinovich.
The basic idea is that
instead of you needing to
pick one of these filter sizes
or pulling you want and
committing to that,
you can do them all
and just contact
all the outputs and
let the network learn
whatever parameters
it wants to use
whatever combinations of
these filter sizes it wants.
Now, it turns out that there's
a problem with the
inception there,
as we've described it here,
which is computational cost.
On the next slide, let's figure
out what's the
computational cost of
this five-by-five
filter resulting
in this block over here.
Just focusing on the
five by five part
on the previous slide,
we had this input a 288
by 28 by 192 block,
and you implement a five
by five same convolution
with 32 filters output
28 by 28 by 32.
On the previous slide,
I had drawn this as
a thin purple slide,
but I'm just I draw this as
a more normal-looking
blue block here.
Let's look at the
computational cost
of outputting this
20 by 20 by 32.
You have 32 filters because
the output has 32 channels,
and each filter is going
to be five by five by 192.
The output size is
20 by 20 by 32,
and so you need to compute
28 by 28 by 32 numbers,
and for each of them,
you need to do this
many multiplications,
five by five by 192.
The total number of
multipliers you need
is the number of
to compute each of
the output values
times the number of output
values you need to compute.
If you multiply out
all these numbers,
this is equal to 120 million.
While you can do 120 million
multipliers on a
modern computer,
this is still a pretty
expensive operation.
On the next slide, you see how
using the idea of
one-by-one convolutions,
which you learned about
in the previous video,
you'll be able to reduce
the computational cost
by about a factor of 10 to
go from about 120
million multipliers
to about one tenth of that.
Please remember the number 120,
so you can compare it with what
you see on the next slide, 128.
Here's an alternative
architecture
for inputting
twenty-eight by 20 by
192 and outputting 28 by 20
by 32 which is following.
You're going to
input the volume,
use a one-by-one convolution,
to reduce the volume to
a 16 channels instead
of 192 channels,
and then on this
much smaller volume,
run your five-by-five
convolution
to give you your final output.
Notice, the input and output
dimensions are still the same.
You input 28 by 20 by 182
and output 28 by 28 by two,
same as the previous line.
But what we've done
is we've taken
this huge volume we
had on the left,
and we've shrunk it to
this much smaller
intermediate volume,
which is only has 16
instead of 192 channels.
Sometimes this is called
a bottleneck layer.
I guess because a bottleneck
is usually the smallest
part of something.
I guess if you have a glass
bottle that looks like this,
then this is I guess
where the core goes.
Then the bottleneck is the
smallest part of this bottle.
In the same way, the
bottleneck layer
is the smallest part
of this network,
where you strength
the representation
before increasing
the size again.
Now, let's look at the
computational costs involved.
To apply this
one-by-one convolution,
we have 16 filters.
Each of the filters
is going to be
of dimension one by one by 192.
This 192 matches that 192.
The cost of computing this 28
by 28 by 16 volume
is going to be,
well, you need
this many outputs.
For each of them, you need
to do 192 multiplications.
I could have written one
times one times 192, is this?
If you multiply this out,
this is 2.4 million.
It is about 2.4 million.
How about the second?
That's the cost
of this first
convolutional layer.
The cost of this second
convolutional layer will be that.
Well, you have
this many outputs,
28 by 28 by two.
Then for each of the outputs,
you have to apply a
five-by-five by
16-dimensional filter.
Five by five by 16,
and if we multiply that
out is equal to 10.0.
The total number of
multiplications you
need to do is the sum of those,
which is 12.4 million
multiplications.
If you compare this with what
we had on the previous slide,
you reduce the
computational cost
from about 120
million multipliers
down to about one-tenth of that
to 12.4 million multiplications.
The number of additions
you need to do is
about very similar to
the number of multiplications
you need to do,
so that's why I'm just counting
the number of multiplications.
To summarize, if you're
building a layer of
a neural network and you
don't want to have to decide,
do you want a one by one or
three by three or five by
five, or pulling layer,
the inception module
lets you say,
let's do them all and
let's concate the results.
Then we ran to the problem
of computational
cost and which you
saw here was how using a
one-by-one convolution,
you can create this
bottleneck layer
thereby reducing the
computational cost significantly.
Now, you might be wondering,
does shrinking down
the representation
size so dramatically,
does it hurt the performance
of your neural network?
It turns out that so long as you
implement this bottleneck
layer so that within reason,
you can shrink down
the representation
size significantly,
and it doesn't seem to
hurt the performance,
but saves you a lot
of computation.
So this is the key of these
are the key ideas of
the inception module.
Let's put them together
and in the next video show
you what the full inception
network looks like.